[The Heir]
[Episode 32]
Zhen,
when you were little,
you often sneaked in here to play,
didn't you?
No.
I only sneaked in once.
My mother caught me
and dragged me out immediately.
Come.
Follow me.
Come, come in.
Zhen.
This is the forbidden area of Li Ink.
Take a good look...
at Li Ink's treasures.
The Ink Vault
is the foundation
of Li family's century-old legacy.
Despite facing internal troubles
and external threats,
ups and downs,
we have survived
because of them.
Lushan Pine Ink.
Zhongjiang's Ink.
So many ancient inks.
Zhen.
Come.
Offer this Sihe Ink
to our Founding Master.
It's because of these
that our Li Ink
can be passed down for generations.
This is what people of Li Ink
will defend
with our lives.
Zhen.
The Li family's legacy
and the Li family's foundation
all lies in these few words:
ink-making techniques.
With it,
people of Li Ink
can get through whatever
hardships and difficulties we experience.
What allows Li Ink to survive
is the technique and spirit.
You must remember this.
I will.
Li Zhen,
it is you
who brought the hope of rebirth
to our Li Ink.
Today,
I am
going to hand over
Li family and Li Ink to you
in front of Founding Master.
You must protect it.
You deserve it.
Seventh Grandmother,
I will do my best—
I swear to protect the Li family
and carry on the legacy of Li Ink.
Rujun.
It's windy at the dock.
Drink this ginger soup
to ward off the cold.
Zhen
is very different
this time she's back.
She told me about the selection
in Nanjing.
From what I heard,
it was a test of
understanding people's hearts.
No one in our Li family except Zhen
is so
observant.
Zhen has her plans.
She looks calm on the surface,
but she acts boldly
yet thoughtfully.
That is the demeanor of a master.
Of course.
She follows the path you laid out for her.
Of course she is just like you.
No, no. No.
She tempered herself through hardships.
Everyone thinks
I was shielding her.
But
I was the one
who was the one most ruthless to her.
I knew very well
she would suffer endless grievances
if I make her carry on
the Li family's legacy,
yet I forcibly dragged her back.
Her journey
has been too tough.
I was thinking,
as she runs forward alone in the future,
no one can stop her anymore.
The burden on your shoulders
can finally be lifted.
Just now,
when I handed her the key
in the Ink Vault,
I saw her expression.
She's going to establish her own school.
She really resembles you a bit
from when you were a young girl.
That feels like a lifetime ago.
You still remember.
It's a pity.
Your whole life
and your talent
are wasted in that high wall.
Rujun.
It's no pity.
I've lived two lives in this lifetime.
I'm content.
The banquet is about to start.
Finish this ginger soup quickly,
and go out to celebrate with your Zhen.
Everyone.
I invited you all to gather here today
for 3 celebrations.
First,
Li Ink has won the Noble Consort's favor,
obtaining the ink supply rights
for the Princess's Mansion,
taking Li Ink to the next level.
Great!
Good!
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Congratulations!
-Congratulations.
-Thank you.
Zhengyou.
You've witnessed
the whole process in Nanjing.
This is your first major event
since joining the ink workshop.
With this glass of wine,
I toast to you.
Congratulations on
completing your apprenticeship.
Thank you, Zhen.
Come.
Zhengyou has made it.
Second,
Li Ink Workshop opened in Nanjing.
Li Ink has stepped out of Huizhou,
marching towards a broader world.
Zhengshen is still tending Nanjing’s shop.
Master Qi.
Nanjing is also partially thanks to you.
You and Zhengshen have worked hard.
With this glass of wine,
I toast to you.
Third,
the Li family has welcomed back
our ancestors' Sihe Ink.
The Sihe Ink
has Li Ink's soul.
With the ink back, the soul is back.
Good!
-Good, good.
-Good.
Good.
Zhen.
Li Ink has come this far—
with the road ahead wide
and the people united—
all thanks to you.
I am deeply honored by the love
of all the respected elders,
and will never
let Seventh Grandmother's trust down.
I will continue to lead Li Ink forward,
Before heaven and earth,
before everyone...
With this glass of wine,
I toast to you all.
Come, drink!
Thank you all!
Zhen.
Can I have a look
at Sihe Ink?
Third Master Chen,
stop thinking about our family's ink.
Just drink.
This Jinshui...
Third Grandfather, drink first.
Finish your glass before we talk.
-All right
-Drink up.
Seventh Grandmother.
Come.
I'll go toast another glass.
President Hu.
I would like to toast to you.
Huizhou's ink industry has been
all thanks to you these years.
Manager Zhen.
The Literary Association
is also benefiting from this.
Third Grandfather.
I'm here to toast to you.
Thank you for your care
for me all these years.
It's my pleasure.
I thank you two.
Come, come.
Eat and drink well today.
I'm telling you, drink less.
Who drinks like this?
Hold this.
Pour wine for me.
Come.
Grandpa, Uncle Jingdong.
I'm here to toast you.
Drink slowly.
Grandpa, drink slowly.
Mother.
Eldest Aunt.
Third Aunt.
Sister-in-law.
Aunt Chunhua.
Come, I toast to you.
Come.
I'm drinking up!
Slow down, be careful.
Look at our little Zhengrun.
Master Qi.
Aunt.
I toast to you.
Thank you for taking care of our Zhen.
Come to our house when you have time.
I'll cook a few dishes,
and we can drink at home.
Tell her to drink less.
I've been pouring very little.
So cute. Who put this on you?
Let me kiss you.
Here.
Another kiss.
Did you drink too much?
Go ahead with your business.
Well...
Xianglan.
Zhengshen sent a letter from Nanjing.
It arrived while you
were still on the boat.
He repeatedly urged
that the letter for you
shouldn't be opened
or peeked at.
Here you go.
Thank you.
My dearest Xianglan!
Give the letter back to me!
Shut up!
All right, all right.
Please have a seat.
Sit.
Hua'er, stop right there!
Father.
Hua'er is bullying me.
You were
grinning from ear to ear.
Take your seat.
I have something important.
Go.
Seventh Old Madam!
All of you are here.
Seventh Old Madam.
Congratulations
for securing of the ink supplier right
for the Princess's Mansion.
This brings glory
to our Huizhou ink industry.
Thank you, Lord Yan.
I used Madam Wang's connections
and hired the best theatrical troupe.
They have been waiting at the stage
for a long time.
I especially invite you,
Old Madam, to do us the honor
of watching the play together.
Thank you, Lord Yan
for going such trouble to arrange this.
Since you arrived,
you haven't even sat down
for a proper drink.
I feel bad about it.
How... How about this?
I'll take Zhen
and my female family members
to go watch the play.
This way, you can sit here comfortably
and enjoy drinking with everyone.
How about that?
That's great!
I'm happy today.
My granddaughters
and daughters-in-law,
let's have a drink to warm up first.
Old Madam.
This theatrical troupe today
was invited to celebrate
the joy of Li Ink.
Please choose a play
for everyone's entertainment.
Cuiqiao, thank you.
So many.
"Baihua Presents a Sword."
When I was young,
my friends and I
loved watching this play the most.
After watching this play, my friends and I
would imitate, recite,
and dance it every day.
I still remember.
♪ Flowers and dew ♪
♪ The moon changes ♪
Bravo!
Beautifully sang!
I was
running out of breath.
I couldn't tell at all.
And I was out of tune too.
But...
But those past events...
they are vivid in my mind.
Every time I watch this play,
I'll be happy for days.
So which play do you
want to listen to today?
Today I'll request for
"The Tale of Two Heroes."
Yes, Old Madam.
♪ I, Liang Hongyu ♪
♪ As Wuzhu launched
an army against our borders ♪
♪ The people are in misery ♪
♪ I'll fight with the General ♪
♪ And Jin soldiers in Jinshan today ♪
Zhen.
Liang Hongyu is so heroic and valiant.
I really admire her.
Liang Hongyu defends the country,
while our Seventh Grandmother
is the Head of the House and manager.
Both of them are role models for women.
Now,
my Zhen,
you are the manager.
Good!
♪ I can't help but feel regretful
seeing these cunning invaders roaring ♪
♪ Hold the armor, get on the horse,
and wield your sword ♪
♪ The female celestial demon
comes down from the highest heaven ♪
♪ Just look at how powerful I am
fighting this war ♪
Bravo!
The beating drums and sounding gongs
are so magnificent,
that they make me, Wang Rujun,
extremely excited.
Liang Hongyu,
the war drums beat
as the soldiers march to battle—
such boundless heroism.
I'm tired of sitting.
I want to get down and walk.
Put me down.
Seventh Grandmother.
Grandmother, it's is already winter.
It's getting cold.
If you want to walk,
let's go take a look
at Nanjing's shop
next spring, okay?
Exactly, Mother.
The night road is hard to walk on.
You should get back in the sedan chair.
Go back.
I insist on walking.
Okay.
I want to walk today,
right now.
This street,
go straight ahead and it leads
to the Li family's ink workshop.
When I married into the Li family
and just became the daughter-in-law,
I went in and out countless times.
Whether it was windy, raining, or hailing,
I was always running
to deliver food to my Jintai.
And then I would
run back
to pacify
Jingyuan in swaddling clothes.
The past days were good.
There was hope.
Nowadays,
I, the daughter-in-law,
have become a mother-in-law.
I am your mother-in-law,
and I've become your Seventh Grandmother.
With you two accompanying me,
not to mention walking home together,
even if we walk to Xin'an River
and take a swim, it would be fine!
Seventh Grandmother,
why did you drink so much today?
I...
I miss Jintai.
Let's go.
With you two protecting me,
how could I not make it home?
It's been a long time
since I felt as happy
as I do tonight.
Zhen,
thank you.
I want to ask you,
are you happy?
Protecting the Li family
is my fate
but not necessarily yours.
I want you
to go for your own goal.
I hope you can boldy
pursue your own happiness.
Seventh Grandmother,
coming to this family was my own choice.
In this family,
I am very happy.
Good.
Seventh Grandmother,
do you still remember?
When I was little,
when my parents went into the mountains,
I would run over to sleep with you.
Back then,
you'd always sang a nursery rhyme to me.
Of course I remember.
♪ Corn pastry ♪
Seventh Grandmother,
let me sing it for you.
Sleep well tonight,
and I'll buy you
a corn pastry tomorrow morning, okay?
Okay, okay.
♪ Step on the fire ♪
[The melody is inspired by a folk song
in Huizhou, "Rice and Wheat Grinding."]
♪ We hold corn pastry in our hands ♪
♪ Eat the pork in a bowl ♪
♪ I'm living a life of bliss, like a god ♪
♪ Step on the fire ♪
♪ We hold corn pastry in our hands ♪
♪ Eat the pork in a bowl ♪
♪ I'm living a life of bliss, like a god ♪
♪ Step on the fire ♪
♪ We hold corn pastry in our hands ♪
Seventh Grandmother,
I bought the corn pastry.
Wake up.
Smell it, isn't it fragrant?
Seventh Grandmother, wake up.
Seventh Grandmother!
[He Garden]
[The spirit tablet of
the paternal grandmother, Wang Rujun]
Guests may pay condolences.
Seventh Old Madam,
may you rest in peace.
Rujin,
in the end, I'm the only one...
left...
in this generation.
Letting me live to the end
is also to repay
Sixth Brother,
Seventh Brother,
and Seventh Sister-in-law's
kindness to Jinshui.
You have protected Li Ink
all your life.
You have lived up to
to the saying "upright and honorable."
Seventh Sister-in-law,
rest in peace.
Reunite with Seventh Brother.
[Li's Ancestral Hall]
Wang Rujun,
the matriarch of the Li family,
was respectful and cautious all her life.
She devoted
all her efforts to the Li family
and achieved outstanding merits.
Today, the Li family
wishes to hang her portrait
in the ancestral hall.
We specially open the ancestral hall
to pay respects to the ancestors.
Kneel!
Bow!
Rise!
Up!
Kneel!
Bow!
Rise!
Hang the portrait!
Invite the spirit to take its seat.
[The spirit tablet of Wang Rujun]
You must be exhausted,
holding on for so long.
I'm fine.
I took over Li Ink
from Seventh Grandmother.
Now I must shoulder the responsibility
of the Li family and Li Ink.
If I let myself be
too immersed in painful and depression,
Seventh Grandmother
won't be able to rest in peace.
I know
you've always been strong.
But now that everyone is gone,
if you are sad,
you should just cry it out.
Qi Jiu.
My Seventh Grandmother is gone.
I don't have a grandmother anymore.
I don't have Seventh Grandmother anymore.
You'll feel better after crying.
So Manager Zhen and Master Qi...
are already so deeply in love.
Granny,
let me help you pick them up.
Your legs aren't very agile.
Don't pick those up.
Just consider it as a tip
from the Seventh Old Madam
to the wandering ghosts on the road.
Thank you for your help.
With the way I look,
I must have scared you.
I'll leave right away.
I recognize you.
You recognize me?
Yes.
I recognize you.
You are Doggie's grandmother.
When I was staying at
the Li Ink Workshop,
I heard Doggie say
that his granny's cooking
is the best in the world.
It made me so envious.
Doggie
mentioned
that there was a Master Qi in Li Ink
who used to live in the ink workshop.
Is that...
That's me, Qi Jiu.
Qi Jiu?
Are you
the ninth child in your family?
No, no.
I...
am an orphan.
My close relatives passed away early.
This name was given to me by my brothers
out there.
I see.
Forgive my presumption.
No, it's fine.
Granny,
it's cold and windy outside.
You should go back in and rest.
I will take my leave first.
[Nanjing]
Mr. Wu.
Why is it 30% more
than what I mentioned?
The path you pointed out
is truly a clear one.
We've already run it successfully twice.
This
is to show my respect to you.
Please continue to look after me
in the future, Mr. Wu.
This is all thanks to
your own intelligence, Mr. Tian.
You figured out
this path's method yourself.
It has nothing to do
with me at all.
How could it have nothing to do with you?
It's all thanks to your efforts
in smoothing things over—
It has nothing to do with you at all.
It was all my own idea,
a path I came up with myself.
But don't worry, Mr. Wu.
There is
nothing wrong with this silver.
The collected Japanese silver...
has already been dealt with.
It's been laundered completely clean.
Rest assured.
Good.
You are very thoughtful, Mr. Tian.
Mr. Tian,
you are a man of great talent.
With such courage and strategy,
in the future,
your prospects are undoubtedly boundless.
You flatter me, Mr. Wu.
Please.
Mr. Tian.
There is one thing
I need to remind you.
Please, go ahead.
You and I both walk in the light.
Our hands
must remain absolutely clean.
They cannot be tainted with any dirt.
Those loose threads in the dark
should be pinned on others.
If someone goes against you
and tries to defame you,
then...
I understand.
Thank you for the reminder, Mr. Wu.
Speaking of which,
there is one more thing.
I would like to ask you
for a small favor, Young Master Wu.
Last time,
we let that Qi Jiu escape by sheer luck.
Count himself lucky.
But strangely,
afterward, he had no reaction at all.
He didn't report
to the authorities or investigate.
The more I think about it,
the more suspicious he seems.
So I wanted to ask you, Mr. Wu,
to help out again
and thoroughly check his background
to prevent future trouble.
My father has some connections
in the Ministry of Revenue.
Investigating someone
is a small matter.
Mr. Wu.
I, Tian Benchang,
today acknowledge you
as my own older brother.
In the future, for every part I get,
you will get two parts.
Brother Tian,
how can the small
Directorate of Imperial Household
possibly keep you?
In the future,
when you achieve your grand plans,
don't forget me, my friend.
You are joking.
You flatter me, Mr. Wu.
Come.
Brother.
We can't do this.
If someone finds out,
we'll be beheaded.
You're the one who came to Nanjing
And you were the one begging
to do business with me.
Now you're scared?
I didn't know we would be trading
with foreigners before I came.
So what?
Now that you know,
you're backing out?
Open the door.
Mr. Tian, everything is inside.
Leave the stuff here.
Wait outside.
Come here.
Stamp this for me.
Brother, I didn't bring my name seal.
Didn't I tell you to bring it?
Yes,
but I forgot.
Brother!
Stamp it.
Stamp it!
Brother, I dare not.
Brother!
Brother, I dare not!
Get people to transport the ink!
I was originally worried
that there'd be no one to tend the shop
in Nanjing
with me coming back for the funeral.
But it's all thanks to to Clerk Qi's help.
He immediately sent a manager over.
He seems very reliable,
so I could rush back with a peace of mind.
When I returned,
several types of ink in the shop
were almost out of stock.
It's been a long time since then.
We need to restock quickly.
Since expensive inks
are selling well in Nanjing,
let's bring
more ancient lacquer-soot ink this time.
The spring examination is approaching.
Origin and Shizi Ink will sell fast,
so prepare some of those too.
Okay.
Seems like the inks
will be ready today.
I'll go say goodbye to Xianglan,
and leave tomorrow.
Manager Zhen.
Master.
The mines in the southeast are rioting.
The refugees fled to Huizhou.
What?